Shamsuddin Altamash Shaikh

Module Lead Web Application Development

Shamsuddin Altamash Shaikh

B802,Green Tower, Near Bhavans College, Andheri (W), Mumbai - 400058

+91 9820659902 altu9594@gmail.com

A Web Developer with 4.5 years of experience in designing, developing, maintaining and managing products and loves to do R&D and contribute at each stack level. Proven ability in optimizing web functionality that improves data retrieval and workflow efficiencies.

Skills

PHP,HTML5,Css,JQuery,Adwords,Node JS,Rest API,Angular Js 2,Cakephp,Laravel,Lumen,Codelgniter,MySQL,Mssql,ElasticSearch,AWS Services,Linux,DNS,Java,Android,J2ME,Web Optimization,Unit Test,Git,Redis,Memcache,Logstash,Wordpress,Wordpress Plugins

Experience

Media.net / Module Lead Web Application Development

OCTOBER 2018 - PRESENT, MUMBAI

Media.net / Web Developer

SEPTEMBER 2015 - OCTOBER 2018, MUMBAI

Media.net / Associate Web Developer

JULY 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2015. MUMBAI

Projects

Accounting

OCTOBER 2014 - PRESENT(In Maintenance Mode)

Technologies Used: Cakephp,Apache,Mssql,HTML,CSS,Rest API,JQuery and bootstrap.

KYC

JUNE 2015 - October 2016

Technologies Used: Cakephp, Apache, Mssql.

IP2GEO API

MAY 2017 - PRESENT,

Technologies Used: PHP,APACHE,Mysql and redis.

SEM(Search Engine Monetization) Projects

JUNE 2017 - PRESENT

This product helps in monetizing the search as well as display traffic, it also helps in monetizing the traffic from social and native platforms.

Bulk Category, Tags Update Wordpress Plugin

JUNE 2017 - PRESENT

Mammoth API

JUNE 2017 - PRESENT

A Rest API which takes docx as an input and converts it to HTML.

Technologies Used: Node JS.

Screenshot API

JUNE 2017 - PRESENT

A Rest API which takes an url as an input returns the screenshot of the current url in desktop and mobile view.

Technologies Used: Node JS.

Wordpress Dropbox Plugin

JUNE 2017 - PRESENT

Wordpress Custom Cache Plugin

DEC 2018 - PRESENT

Education

M.H Saboo Siddik College of Engineering / B.E Information

Technology - 75%

AUGUST 2010 - JUNE 2014, MUMBAI

Rizvi College of Science / H.S.C - 75.17%

AUGUST 2008 - FEBRUARY 2010, MUMBAI

S.T Theresa's High School / S.S.C - 75.84%

JUNE 1995 - MARCH 2008, MUMBAI.

Certifications

Internships

and

Web Technologist Level 1 from Suven Consultants

Android Certified Programming from Suven Consultants.

Intelligent Ads using PHP, Peoples Corner in Android.

Hobbies

Cricket, Music, Swimming, Travelling and Trekking